# SLONE **SALERNO**

Crystal Lake, IL 60012 | H: 815-975-7037 | slonemariesalerno@gmail.com

### **SUMMARY**

I am currently a senior at the University of Missouri majoring in Convergence Journalism with an emphasis in Multi-Media Production. I have worked in several newsrooms on campus gaining experience. I produced text, audio, photo and video stories for my classes and newsrooms. I am interested in a career in that allows me to use the skills I've learned in the classroom and newsrooms that gives me a creative outlet.

#### **SKILLS**

- Linear editing experience using Adobe Premier
- Proficient in photo editing on Photoshop
- Proficient in audio editing on Adobe Audition
- AP Style news writing
- Proficient in OPUS

#### **EXPERIENCE**

05/2017 to 12/2018 Cashier

**Univeristy Of Missouri** — Columbia, MO

I worked as a cashier and ticket salesman at the University of Missouri Box office where I would use three computer systems to search and pull tickets. I would also work venues at the Missouri Theater. I spoke with customers in person and on the phone daily.

07/2017 to 08/2017

Nanny

**Sharmistha Bhalla** — Columbia, MO

I was a nanny for three children under ten, one with special needs. I would drive them to practices and take them to the pool. I would also help them get ready for bed and make food when necessary.

05/2019 to 08/2019

Intern

WGN News - Chicago, IL

I interned at WGN News in Chicago for the summer. I worked closely with the segment producer. I would file video clips into the computer for the producers and editors, cut video for the website and write stories for the segments. I would also help direct the guests during their segments. While I was there I also had the opportunity to shadow writers and write a few news stories, go into the field with a reporter and observe the control room.

## **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

05/2016

**High School Diploma** 

**Prairie Ridge High School** — Crystal Lake, IL Columbia

Convergence Journalism Multi-Media Production

**University of Missouri** — Columbia, MO

## **ACTIVITIES AND HONORS**

Dean's list Spring 2017, Fall 2017

## WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

• slonesalerno.com

#### **WORK I'VE DONE**

https://www.komu.com/news/backpack-policy-at-mexico-middle-schoolaids-in-gun-discovery-/page/24

https://www.komu.com/news/mu-law-professors-join-peers-in-letter- opposing-kavanaugh

https://www.columbiamissourian.com/visuals/videos/mothersingers-group-prepares-for-christmas-program/youtube\_fc4871fa-e916-11e8-be46-63e8aa31357f.html

http://www.kbia.org/post/facing-ticking-clock-missourians-seek-preserve-black-history